## HARSH SIKKA

#### **PROFILE**

Cognitive Scientist interested in applying technology to improve the human condition through the implementation of efficient brain computer interface. Experienced in technical fields including Software Engineering, Web Development, User Experience research, Publishing and Deep Learning.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### FOUNDER, PROGRESS; SAN DIEGO, CA - 2015-PRESENT

Established Progress, an academic journal dedicated to the publication of findings and projects that advance and fulfill human potential in the fields of Cognitive Science, Computer Science, and Biotechnology.

- Designed Editorial Process and assembled current Board consisting of UCSD Faculty and Students.
- Worked with PubPub team at MIT to design and build site according to platform constraints.
- Led transition from continuous publishing to Issue format due to volume of submissions.
- Released first issue at http://progress.pubpub.org/collection/design\_perspective

## PRODUCT MANAGEMENT INTERN, SIKKA SOFTWARE; SAN JOSE, CA - 2015

Worked to lead and direct the implementation of a novel, innovative, and new to market product fundamentally changing healthcare infrastructure.

- Implemented prototypes to guide design and development teams.
- Managed transition to Agile Software methodologies.
- Provided market and competitor analysis.
- Oversaw hybrid matrix structure and allocation of human resources.
- Used weighted score models to balance corporate mission and novel innovation.

## CONTRIBUTOR, THE HUFFINGTON POST; NYC, NEW YORK - 2016-PRESENT

Frequently writes about research and developments in the fields of Computer Science, Cognitive Science, and engineering. Also writes about Entrepreneurship, VC, and

emerging markets. Popular articles include the following topics:

- Al and Deep Learning
- Product breakthroughs due to the evolution of AI
- Brain Computer Interface and the Neural Lace

#### **RESEARCH & PROJECTS**

#### ATHENA - 2015-PRESENT

Athena is an assistive AI focused on helping those with impairments and disabilities, Athena's current implementation functions to provide a conversational user experience that can answer simple factual questions both textually and verbally, so as to assist those with hearing impairments or visual impairments.

- Athena is also currently being tested for use in early childhood development, rewarding inquisitiveness with conversationally presented interaction and information.
- Uses JSON to breakdown queries into information quanta that it can then sort information by.
- Currently competing for the IBM Xprize 2020, with the theme of healthcare and human assistance.
- Deployed at harshsikka123.github.io/Athena-Al

## COGNITIVE DESIGN THESIS: PHYTASOL - 2016-PRESENT

Designed and implemented a algae photobioreactor that effectively creates completely renewable algae biodiesel at the individual scale. Followed proper research methods over a ten week period, informing design and implementation of bioreactor.

- The bioreactor reclaims its own waste CO2 from the atmosphere, and can be assembled in under 40\$ with common household parts and water.
- Currently researching implementation scale.
- Also researching the bioreactor's effects on the quality of life of low income families in impoverished communities.

 Possible future research includes bioreactor demonstration in elementary and middle schools for alternative energy education.

#### TRITON ENTREPRENEURS, FOUNDER - 2014-2016

Started the first student run startup accelerator at UCSD. Focused on providing business and technical resources to both faculty and students on campus, Triton Entrepreneurs established networking events, pitch competitions, company presentations, job fairs and an annual Entrepreneurial Summit that highlights successful entrepreneurs.

- Counseled other student entrepreneurs on various technical and business decisions.
- Gave guest lectures to management science students on Venture Capital, bootstrapping, and innovation.
- Drafted constitution, established bylaws.
- Official UCSD Organization page: http://studentorg.ucsd.edu/RdOnlyDetail.aspx? data=6297

### CORAL, PROJECT LEAD - 2016-PRESENT

Building a revolutionary platform for crowdsourced learning, centering on learning through the experiences of others. Customers will be able to navigate through the work of those who have pursued similar goals, from computer science to tap dancing. Creators can also benefit through sponsorship, guaranteeing the emergence of a new paradigm in education technology.

## THE HUMAN DIRECTORY, PROJECT LEAD - 2015-PRESENT

Aimed at solving the problem of impermanence in human society, the human directory serves as a time capsule for those who want to leave behind a mark of themselves for generations to come. The projects Beta just finished, and release is projected for December of 2016.

## **EDUCATION**

UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA, SAN DIEGO - BA COGNITIVE SCIENCE, 2016

# SKILLS

Research	Software Engineering			Writing	Algorithms		UI Design
Javascript	HTML & CSS Pr			duct Management		Java	
Journal Formatting UX Des			ign				